Tomie dePaola Collection
© 2005 University of Connecticut
- Series III: Art Work, undated, 1949-1999
  - Art Work done at Pratt
    - Figure Study: woman - ink and pastel on paper, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 9:, Folder 224)
    - Figure Study - ink on paper, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 9:, Folder 225)
    - Figure Study: woman standing - charcoal & pastel, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 9:, Folder 226)
    - Figure Study: two men - charcoal and pastel, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 9:, Folder 227)
    - Figure Study: woman standing, woman sitting -charcoal and pastel on paper, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 9:, Folder 228)
    - Figure Study - charcoal & pastel on paper, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 9:, Folder 229)
    - “Rooftops at Pratt” -casein on masonite, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 9:, Folder 230)
    - “Mary Magdalene” -oil on board, 1954 (Box 9:, Folder 231)
    - “Votive lights” -casein on board, 1954 (Box 9:, Folder 232)
    - “The Portrait of a Young Actress” -pen & ink, 1954 (Box 9:, Folder 233)
    - “Crowd Scene problem” -tempera on paper, 1953-1954 (Box 9:, Folder 234)
    - Figure Study -charcoal on paper, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 9:, Folder 235)
    - Figure Study: woman seated -ink & watercolor, 1954 (Box 9:, Folder 236)
    - Figure Study: man seated -ink and pastel on paper, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 10:, Folder 237)
    - Figure Study: back view of woman seated -ink & pastel on newspaper, 1953 (Box 10:, Folder 238)
    - Figure Study: woman seated & woman standing -charcoal on paper, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 10:, Folder 239)
    - Figure Study: woman seated -charcoal on paper, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 10:, Folder 240)
    - Figure Study: back view of woman -pen & ink, ca. 1952-1953 (Box 10:, Folder 241)
    - Figure Study: woman -charcoal on paper, ca. 1952-1953 (Box 10:, Folder 241A)
    - “Life of Christ” mural project -tempera on board, ca. 1953-1954 (Box 10:, Folder 242)
    - Figure Study: reclining woman -charcoal & pastel, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 10:, Folder 243)
    - Figure Study: woman with hat -ink & pastel, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 10:, Folder 244)
    - Figure Study: 2 women, man on stool -ink & pastel on paper, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 10:, Folder 245)
    - “Hamlet” design problem -pencil on paper, ca. 1954-1955 (Box 10:, Folder 246)
    - “Lemon-aide” color problem -tempera on board, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 10:, Folder 247)
    - Illustration project: Boy leaping off train -pen & ink on board, ca. 1954-1955 (Box 10:, Folder 248)
    - Figure Study: 3 women -pencil on paper, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 10:, Folder 249)
    - Light pattern: design problem -pencil on paper, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 10:, Folder 250)
    - “Illustrations for Children's books” -pen & colored inks on board, ca. 1952-1952 (Box 10:, Folder 251)
    - Figure Study: reclining woman -charcoal, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 10:, Folder 252)
    - Figure Study: Woman in blue dress -casein on paper, Back side: sketch, 1955 (Box 10:, Folder 253)
    - “Mother and Child” -pen & ink on Bristol, ca. 1950s (Box 10:, Folder 254)
    - “Conflict Problem” -tempera on Bristol, ca. 1953-1954 (Box 10:, Folder 255)
    - Woman & 2 Cats -tempera on paper, ca. 1952-1953 (Box 10:, Folder 256)
    - “Hall Street from rooftops” -pen & ink on Bristol, ca. 1952-1953 (Box 10:, Folder 257)
    - “Portrait of a house” -watercolor, pen & ink, ca. 1953-1954 (Box 10:, Folder 258)
    - Head of girl -watercolor, pastel, pen & ink, ca. 1953-1954 (Box 10:, Folder 259)
    - Back side: Harlequin & Columbine -wash-out
    - “Brownstone Stoop” -pen & ink, wash on Bristol, ca. 1952-1953 (Box 11:, Folder 260)
    - “Littlest Angel” book project (4 drawings) pen & ink, ca. 1955-1956 (Box 11:, Folder 261)
    - “Many dawns ago...” from “All of Our Angels”, ca. 1955-1956 (Box 11:, Folder 261A)
    - “All of Our Angels” sketch book, Pratt, ca. 1955-1956 (Box 11:, Folder 261B)
    - “All of Our Angels”, senior book illustration project, ca. 1955-1956 (Box 11:, Folder 261C)
    - “+Ut In Omnibus Glorificetur Deus” -senior book illustration project, ca. 1955-1956 (Box 11:, Folder 261D)
    - “Christmas in New York” -illustration project, ca. 1955-1956 (Box 11:, Folder 261E)
    - Mary Magdalene -tempera & gold leaf, ca. 1955-1956 (Box 12:, Folder 262A)
    - Sketches for Mural project -tempera on board, ca. 1955-1956 (Box 12:, Folder 262B)
    - Boy at Beach -tempera on watercolor paper, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 12:, Folder 262C)
    - Procession Problem -casein on board, ca. 1953-1954 (Box 12:, Folder 262D)
    - Portrait -watercolor, pen & ink on illustration board, ca. 1953-1954 (Box 12:, Folder 262)
    - Keyhole -watercolor, pen & ink, ca. 1953-1954 (Box 12:, Folder 263)
    - Seated woman reading newspaper -pen & ink, ca. 1952-1953 (Box 12:, Folder 264)
    - “Mary Poppins...” -watercolor, pen & ink, ca. 1952-1953 (Box 12:, Folder 265)
    - Girl feeding chickens -pen & ink on tracing paper, ca. 1952-1953 (Box 12:, Folder 266)
    - “Dick Whitington's Cat” -watercolor, pen & ink, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 12:, Folder 267)
    - Children, Virgin & child -scratchboard, undated (Box 12:, Folder 268)
    - “The Richest of the Poor” -book jacket design -pen & ink & Bourges paper on illustration board, ca. 1954-55 (Box 12:, Folder 269)
    - “Risen Christ” -ink and pastel on paper, ca. 1955-1956 (Box 12:, Folder 270)
    - “Virgin” -ink and pastel on newspaper, ca. 1955-1956 (Box 12:, Folder 271)
    - “St. Francis” -scratchboard, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 12:, Folder 272)
    - Flower study -watercolor on paper, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 12:, Folder 273)
    - Plant studies (front and back) -watercolor on paper, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 12:, Folder 274)
    - “The Way of the Cross” (5 drawings) -scratchboard, ca. 1955-1956 (Box 12:, Folder 275)
    - Sketches (6), ca. 1952-1956 (Box 12:, Folder 276)
    - Sketches (6), ca. 1952-1956 (Box 12:, Folder 277)
    - Sketches (8), ca. 1952-1956 (Box 12:, Folder 278)
    - Sketches (6), ca. 1952-1956 (Box 12:, Folder 279)
    - Sketches (6), ca. 1952-1956 (Box 12:, Folder 280)
    - Sketch -charcoal on paper, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 12:, Folder 281)
    - Sketches (6), ca. 1952-1956 (Box 12:, Folder 282)
    - Sketches (5), ca. 1952-1956 (Box 12:, Folder 283)
    - Sketches (16), ca. 1952-1956 (Box 12:, Folder 284)
    - Sketches (22), ca. 1952-1956 (Box 12:, Folder 285)
    - Sketches (5) -pencil, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 12:, Folder 286)
    - Sketch -conte crayon on tracing paper, ca. 1952-1953 (Box 12:, Folder 287)
    - Sketches (5) -pencil / charcoal on paper, ca. 1952-1953 (Box 12:, Folder 288)
  - Art Work done at Pratt (oversized) (Box 13)
    - “Veronica's Veil” -tempera on paper, 1955 (Box 13:, Folder 289)
    - Robinson Crusoe project -sepia ink on board, ca. 1955-1956 (Box 13:, Folder 289A)
    - “Temptation of Christ in the Desert” -tempera, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 13:, Folder 289B)
    - Greenwich Village, Richard Lidner project -casein, ca. 1953-1954 (Box 13:, Folder 289C)
    - Painting of Model -oil on board, 1956 (Box 13:, Folder 289D)
    - “Circus” illustration project -casein on board, 1953 (Box 13:, Folder 290)
    - Figure Study: woman -sanguine conte crayon, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 13:, Folder 290A)
    - Figure Study: man standing -charcoal on paper, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 13:, Folder 291B)
    - Figure Study: 2 women -charcoal & pastel, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 13:, Folder 291)
    - Figure Study: 2 women -chalk & pastel, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 13:, Folder 292)
    - Figure Study: Man -charcoal on paper, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 13:, Folder 293)
    - Figure Study: woman seated -charcoal & pastel, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 13:, Folder 294)
    - Sketch book, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 13:, Folder 295)
    - Figure Study: woman's head -charcoal & pastel, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 13:, Folder 296)
    - Figure Study: woman standing -charcoal & pastel, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 13:, Folder 297)
    - Figure Study: woman's head -charcoal & pastel, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 13:, Folder 298)
    - Study for Good Shepherd Fresco -tempera on board, 1955 (Box 13:, Folder 299)
    - Figure Study: reclining woman -charcoal on paper, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 13:, Folder 300)
    - Figure Study: 2 standing women -charcoal on paper, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 13:, Folder 301)
    - Figure Study: sitting woman -charcoal & pastel, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 13:, Folder 302)
    - Figure Study: woman reading -charcoal & pastel, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 13:, Folder 303)
    - Figure Study: reclining woman -charcoal on paper, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 13:, Folder 304)
    - Figure Study: sitting woman -charcoal on paper, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 13:, Folder 305)
    - Figure Study: standing man -charcoal & pastel, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 13:, Folder 306)
    - Figure Study: sitting woman -charcoal on paper, 1954 (Box 13:, Folder 307)
    - Figure Study: two women -charcoal & pastel, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 13:, Folder 308)
    - Figure Study: sitting man -charcoal & pastel, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 13:, Folder 309)
    - Figure Study: sitting woman -charcoal on paper, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 13:, Folder 310)
    - Figure Study: man -charcoal & pastel on paper, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 13:, Folder 311)
    - Figure Study: 2 women -charcoal on paper, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 13:, Folder 312)
    - Figure Study: 2 women- charcoal on paper, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 13:, Folder 313)
    - Figure Study: front of standing woman -charcoal, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 13:, Folder 314)
    - Figure Study: front of standing woman -charcoal, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 13:, Folder 315)
    - Figure Study: Back of standing woman -charcoal, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 13:, Folder 316)
    - Figure Study: standing woman -charcoal & pastel, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 13:, Folder 317)
    - Figure Study: woman's bosom -charcoal on paper, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 13:, Folder 318)
    - Figure Study: sitting woman -charcoal & pastel, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 13:, Folder 319)
    - Figure Study: two women -charcoal on paper, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 13:, Folder 320)
  - Sketch Books (Box 14)
    - ----- (Box 14:, Folder 321)
    - Sketch book, ca. 1965 (Box 14:, Folder 322)
    - Sketch book, Pratt -some drawings not Tomie's, ca. 1954-1956 (Box 14:, Folder 323)
    - Sketch book, Pratt -includes sketch for 1955 painting “Stigmata of Francis of Assisi”, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 14:, Folder 324)
    - Sketch book, undated (Box 14:, Folder 325)
    - Sketch book, ca. 1961-1962 (Box 14:, Folder 326)
    - Sketch book, ca. late 1950s (Box 14:, Folder 327)
    - Pratt & post- Pratt sketch book, ca. 1955 (Box 15:, Folder 328)
    - Sketch book, ca. 1959 (Box 15:, Folder 329)
    - Sketch book, Pratt & Europe, ca. 1955-1956 (Box 15:, Folder 330)
    - Sketch book, England, ca. 1967 (Box 15:, Folder 331)
  - Art Work (Box 16)
    - Mary Magdalen -tempera on paper, 1956 (Box 16:, Folder 332)
    - Girl in blue dress -oil on board, 1950 (Box 16:, Folder 333)
    - Girl in white blouse -oil on board, 1949 (Box 16:, Folder 334)
    - The Milkmaid and her pail -monoprint on paper, 1968 (Box 16:, Folder 335)
    - The Rainbow factory in homage to Thom Klika -rubber stamp, collograpg, watercolor on paper, 1971 (Box 16:, Folder 336)
    - Newspaper Collage -press on type, newspaper, 1968 (Box 16:, Folder 337)
    - Letter Collage -rubber stamp, press on type, 1968 (Box 16:, Folder 338)
    - “Plan for a Garden -Number Four” -pencil & watercolor, 1975 (Box 16:, Folder 339)
    - “The Good Shepherd” -study for fresco, Skowhegan pen & ink on paper, 1955 (Box 16:, Folder 340)
    - Skowhegan landscape -caein on board, 1955 (Box 16:, Folder 341)
    - Caribbean people -for Scholastic Art Award -Opaque watercolor on board, ca. 1951-1952; (3 drawings) (Box 16:, Folder 342)
    - “Fourth of July” -pen & ink & watercolor on board, ca. 1960 (Box 16:, Folder 343)
    - Mother's Day Card -collage: acrylic & photo, 1967 (Box 16:, Folder 344)
    - Woman & Man -etching on paper, ca. 1969-1970 (Box 16:, Folder 345)
    - Sacred Heart -pen & ink on board w/ laquer, ca. 1956-1957 (Box 16:, Folder 346)
    - Capricorn, Gemini, Virgo & Leo -pencil & watercolor on paper, 1974 (Box 16:, Folder 347)
    - Egg tempera on board, ca. 1958-1959 (Box 16:, Folder 348)
    - “Hail Mary” -metal working class, 7th grade., ca. 1946-1947 (Box 17:, Folder 349)
    - Sacred Heart Wooden Figure (missing heart) -cray-pas and nails on wood, 1963 (Box 17:, Folder 350)
    - Items 348-350 are part of a set
    - Sacred Heart Plaque -tempera on wood, ca. 1958-1959 (Box 17:, Folder 351)
    - “Heart” -colograph plate for etching press, 1971 (Box 17:, Folder 352)
    - “Hearts” -colograph plate for etching press, 1971 (Box 17:, Folder 353)
    - “Bird” -colograph plate for etching press, 1971 (Box 17:, Folder 354)
    - Bird, Moon & Tree (4) -etching prints, undated (Box 18:, Folder 355)
    - “The Last Moon” (6) -etching prints, undated (Box 18:, Folder 356)
    - (2) etchings by Mary-Jo McArthy, undated (Box 18:, Folder 357)
    - Witch(?) prints (2), undated (Box 18:, Folder 358)
    - “Horrors” prints (3), 1968 (Box 18:, Folder 359)
    - “M-J, Walter & Me” prints (3), 1968 (Box 18:, Folder 360)
    - “The Moon” prints (6) & watercolor illustration, 1968 (Box 18:, Folder 361)
    - “Lady” prints (4), 1968 (Box 18:, Folder 362)
    - Miscellaneous prints from etchings (4), 1968 (Box 18:, Folder 363)
    - Illustration for etching -woman & fairy, -pen & ink, undated (Box 18:, Folder 364)
    - Drawing of Kiss factory -rubber stamp, pen & ink, watercolor, 1968 (Box 18:, Folder 365)
    - Type Settings “The King and the Golden River”, undated (Box 18:, Folder 366)
    - Type Settings “Palmstroem”, undated (Box 18:, Folder 367)
    - Type Settings “California is a State of Mind”, undated (Box 18:, Folder 368)
    - Type Settings “If Heaven and Earth...”, 1968 (Box 18:, Folder 369)
    - Monoprint with ink sketch of snake, undated (Box 18:, Folder 370)
    - (21) Monoprints, undated (Box 18:, Folder 371)
    - (2) Experimental pen & inks, 1964 (Box 18:, Folder 372)
    - (9) Serigraphs, 1968 (Box 18:, Folder 373)
    - (3) Colographs “David Duchin”, 1973 (Box 18:, Folder 374)
    - Heart over Rainbow, 1974
    - “Christmas 1997” Sheep on glossy card paper (Box 18:, Folder 374A)
  - Posters / Music Albums (Box 19)
    - The Prince of the Dolomites, 1980 (Box 19:, Folder 375)
      - 4 Promotional Illustrated Prints
    - So Full of Deep Joy album promotional print, 1981 (Box 19:, Folder 376)
    - The Cat on the Dovrefell promotional print, undated (Box 19:, Folder 377)
    - Santa's Crash-Bang Christmas promotional print, 1977 (Box 19:, Folder 378)
    - Once Upon a Dinkelsbuhl promotional book mark, undated (Box 19:, Folder 379)
    - Songs of the Fog Maiden promotional jacket text, undated (Box 19:, Folder 380)
    - Big Anthony and the Magic Ring promotional print, 1979 (Box 19:, Folder 381)
    - Strega Nona -promotional print, undated (Box 19:, Folder 382)
    - Strega Nona -oversized promotional cover, undated (Box 19:, Folder 383)
    - Tomie dePaola's Book of Bible Stories poster, 1990 (Box 19:, Folder 384)
    - The Tale of Rabbit and Coyote -poster, 1990 (Box 19:, Folder 385)
    - The Legend of Old Belfana -poster, undated (Box 19:, Folder 386)
    - Nuestra Senora de Guadalupe -poster, 1980 (Box 19:, Folder 387)
    - The Wuggie Norple Story -poster, 1980 (Box 19:, Folder 388)
    - The Kid's Cat Book -poster, 1979 (Box 19:, Folder 389)
    - Tomie dePaola's Mother Goose -poster, undated (Box 19:, Folder 390)
    - Helga's Dowry: A Troll Love Story -poster, 1977 (Box 19:, Folder 391)
    - The Hunter and the Animals -poster, 1981 (Box 19:, Folder 392)
    - Tomie dePaola's Favorite Nursery Tales -poster, undated (Box 19:, Folder 393)
    - Strega Nona's Magic Lessons -poster, 1982 (Box 19:, Folder 394)
    - The Legend of the Bluebonnet -poster, undated (Box 19:, Folder 395)
    - Sing, Pierrot, Sing -poster, 1983 (Box 19:, Folder 396)
    - Tatie's River Journey -poster, undated (Box 19:, Folder 397)
    - Merry Christmas Strega Nona -poster, 1986 (Box 19:, Folder 398)
    - Miracle on 34th Street -poster, 1984 (Box 19:, Folder 399)
    - Bonjour, Mr. Satie -poster, 1991 (Box 19:, Folder 400)
    - The Mysterious Giant of Barletta -poster, 1991 (Box 19:, Folder 401)
    - Tomie dePaola's Book of Christmas Carols -poster, 1987 (Box 19:, Folder 402)
    - Big Anthony & friends -poster, 1989 (Box 19:, Folder 403)
    - Jingle the Christmas Clown -poster, 1992 (Box 19:, Folder 404)
    - The Legend of the Indian Paintbrush -poster, 1988 (Box 19:, Folder 405)
    - Mary, The Mother of Jesus -poster, undated (Box 19:, Folder 406)
    - Patrick, Patron Saint of Ireland -poster, undated (Box 19:, Folder 407)
    - Strega Nona: Her Story as Told by Tomie dePaola- poster, 1996 (Box 19:, Folder 408)
    - Now One Foot, Now the Other- poster, 1981 Spr. (Box 19:, Folder 409)
    - Strega Nona Meets Her Match- poster, undated (Box 19:, Folder 410)
    - The Eagle and the Rainbow- poster, undated (Box 19:, Folder 411)
    - The Mountains of Quilt- promotional poster, 1987 (Box 19:, Folder 411A)
    - The Comic Adventures of Old Mother Hubbard and Her Dog (Box 19:, Folder 411B)
    - Tomie dePaola's Hey Diddle Diddle - poster, 1986 (Box 19:, Folder 412)
    - Tomie dePaola's Mother Goose - poster, 1986 (Box 19:, Folder 413)
    - Kearsage Tomie appearance announcement, 1982 Aug. (Box 19:, Folder 414)
    - NHPO Children's Concert -illustration by Tomie, 1997 (Box 19:, Folder 415)
    - The Kerlan Award booklet -Univ. of Minnesota, 1981 May (Box 19:, Folder 416)
    - Regina Medal Award Announcement & print, 1983 (Box 19:, Folder 417)
    - American Bookseller Children's Book Catalog cover illustration, 1982 Mar. (Box 19:, Folder 418)
    - Colby-Sawyer College Showbill cover illustration, 1982-1983 (Box 19:, Folder 419)
    - French Creek Sheep & Wool Co., catalog cover, 1982 Deca. (Box 19:, Folder 420)
    - Nieman Marcus Catalog cover illustration, 1982 Deca. (Box 19:, Folder 421)
    - Tomie photo on posterboard for autograph session, undated (Box 19:, Folder 422)
    - “CrackerJacks” large Tomie poster, 1976 (Box 19:, Folder 423)
    - “Food Research and Action Center”, 1994 (Box 19:, Folder 424)
    - “Becoming a Tradition...10th Annual Children's Literature Festival” -poster, 1986 (Box 19:, Folder 425)
    - “Tomie dePaola: A Retrospective”, 1986 Nov.-Jan (Box 19:, Folder 426)
    - “Tomie dePaola” poster -original is 159C in Box# 7, undated (Box 19:, Folder 427)
    - “Imagine Your Child with Nothing to Imagine”, undated (Box 19:, Folder 428)
    - “Get Into Books” poster, 1983 (Box 19:, Folder 429)
    - (4) ALA's “Are there any favorable poems about Mothers in law?”, Pet mouse, Alaska, Tarantuala, 1980 (Box 19:, Folder 430)
    - (2)“Info to go at your Library”, “Knowledge...”, undated (Box 19:, Folder 431)
    - Petey & Flossie Hopkin poster, undated (Box 19:, Folder 432)
    - “Campaign to end childhood hunger”, undated (Box 19:, Folder 433)
    - “Book Links” poster, 1991 (Box 19:, Folder 434)
    - “Vanessa-Ann” poster, 1983 (Box 19:, Folder 435)
    - “Imagination Celebration” Exhibit poster, 1988 (Box 19:, Folder 436)
    - “Tomie truns 60” Exhibit poster, 1995 (Box 19:, Folder 437)
    - “Pablo the Cat” Exhibit poster, 1991 (Box 19:, Folder 438)
    - “Down Under, Over Here” Exhibit poster, 1997 (Box 19:, Folder 439)
    - “The Illustrator's Art...” Exhibit poster, 1993 Jan-Mar (Box 19:, Folder 440)
    - “The Art of the Heart Man” Exhibit poster, 1990 Nov-Dec (Box 19:, Folder 441)
    - “Children's Book Activity Fair” -poster, undated (Box 19:, Folder 442)
    - “Celebrate the Magic” poster, 1988 (Box 19:, Folder 443)
    - “A Child's Garden of Verses, Songs...” poster, 1989 Mar. (Box 19:, Folder 444)
  - Sketches (Box 20)
    - (12) Miscellaneous sketches -small, undated (Box 20:, Folder 445)
    - (9) Recognizable sketches from books or themed drawings: Marianna May and Nursey, Journey of a Kiss, Tomie, undated (Box 20:, Folder 446)
    - (21) Miscellaneous sketches w/ poems or writing, undated (Box 20:, Folder 447)
    - (32) Miscellaneous sketches / drawings completed, undated (Box 20:, Folder 448)
    - (27) Miscellaneous sketches, undated (Box 20:, Folder 449)
    - (27) Miscellaneous sketches, undated (Box 20:, Folder 450)
    - (15) Miscellaneous sketches, undated (Box 20:, Folder 451)
    - (8) Miscellaneous sketches, undated (Box 20:, Folder 452)
    - (13) Miscellaneous sketches on tracing paper, undated (Box 20:, Folder 453)
    - Painting - Boy flying kite, oil on canvas, 1963 (Box 21:, Folder 454)
    - Painting -“Moon Flowers” -oil on canvas, 1977 (Box 21:, Folder 455)
    - Painting -“St. Joseph Patron Saint of Workers” -framed oil on canvas, 1963 (Box 21:, Folder 456)
    - Painting- Boy with Sun in background - oil on canvas (Box 21:, Folder 457)
  - Oversized Art Work (Box 22)
    - “When You Go to Delphi Please Bring Me Back...” -pencil & watercolor, 1972 (Box 22:, Folder 458)
    - “There Seems to be an awful lot...” -pencil & watercolor, 1972 (Box 22:, Folder 459)
    - Girl in Bikini -pencil & watercolor, 1965 (Box 22:, Folder 460)
    - “Punch” -pen & ink & pastels, 1967 (Box 22:, Folder 461)
    - “Factory Number One, Factory Number Two” -pencil & watercolor, undated (Box 22:, Folder 462)
- Series IV: Videorecordings, 1990s
  - [Tomie De Paola's birthday celebration]. Recording of birthday celebrations for Tomie De Paola at UCONN on the occasion of De Paola handing over his papers to the Dodd Center. De Paola talks about his art and writing and reads from his books, 26 Fairmount Ave. and Night of Los Posadas., [199-?] (Other Video 229)
  - Part of Jean Fritz, all of Tomie De Paola: 1st Annual Bookfair Teacher's Conference. 1st Annual Bookfair Teacher's Conference. Recorded at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center at the University of Connecticut at Storrs on November 14, 1999. Jean Fritz talks about her historical fiction and the research she puts into it. Tomie De Paola talks about his career including his brief time in a Vermont monastery (Other Video 233)